Appleton Company Records 6516
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series III. FINANCIAL
  - General Account Entries, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    September through October 1870.
  - Accounts Credited to Individuals, 1870 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    October 1870.
  - Day Books, 1831-1833 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    May 30, 1831 through June 29, 1833. Includes entries for goods received and shipped, also hours of employees spent apparently on repairs.
  - Day Books, 1833-1836 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    December 2, 1933 through March 29, 1836. Includes entries for goods received and shipped, also hours of employees spent apparently on repairs.
  - Cash Book Excerpts, 1871 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    August 8, 1871. Items in June and July cash.
  - Notes Discounted, 1843 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    August 32, 1843.
  - Memoranda of Entries on Superintendent's Account, 1867-1870 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    Includes March 1867, every month of 1868 (except March), January and December 1869, and April 1870.
- Series IV. PURCHASING
  - Starch Contracts, 1835-1847 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    May 1, 1835; May 2, 1844; May 24, 1847.
  - Certificates of Damaged Cotton, 1836-1842 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    September 26, 1836; January 10, 1837; March 1, 1842; July 1, 1842; September 13, 1842 (2).
  - Goods Purchased, 1830 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    January and February 1830. Coal and wood used in furnaces and boilers.
  - Goods Purchased, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    February 25, 1832. Trial of wood and coal.
  - Goods Purchased, 1832 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    June 30, 1832. Oil used in Hamilton and Appleton for the twelve months prior.
  - Goods Purchased, 1830-1831 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    February 2, 1831. Wood sued in furnaces beginning Monday November 29, 1830. May 1831. Memo of fuel use from May 1830 to May 1831.
  - Goods Purchased, 1841 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    August 25, 1841. Cost of coal sent to Appleton.
  - Goods Purchased, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    November 30. 1867. Cost of cotton for previous six months.
  - Goods Purchased (Box 3, Folder 83)
    Circa 1830. Cost of whale oil lamp wicks.
  - Goods Purchased (Box 3, Folder 84)
    Prices of Socket Lamps
  - Goods Purchased (Box 3, Folder 85)
    Articles charged to General Expense.
- Series V. SALES
  - Contract for Sale of Cotton Waste to Hurd & Grehore, 1831 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    January 15, 1831.
  - Contract for Consignment of Goods With Upham, Tucker, & Company, 1867 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    November 11, 1867; November 12, 1867; November 13, 1867.
  - Contract for Consignment of Goods With Catlin & Company, 1898 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    February 24, 1898; February 25, 1898; February 28, 1898.
  - Sketch of Sales: Memo of Sales and Goods on Hand, 1868 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    February 7, 1868; May 1968; July 9, 1868; November 30, 1868; December 1868.
  - Sketch of Sales: Memo of Sales and Goods on Hand, 1869 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    February 20, 1869; May 10, 1869; July 12, 1869.
  - Sketch of Sales: Memo of Sales and Goods on Hand, 1870-1871 (Box 3, Folder 91)
    May 13, 1870; May 31, 1870; February 28, 1871; April 11, 1871
  - Sketch of Sales by Upham, Tucker & Company, 1868-1871 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    Eleven sales statements.
- Series VI. LABOR
  - Employment Regulations, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 93)
  - List of Mill Girls Who Left Mill Due to Wage Reductions, 1834 (Box 3, Folder 94)
  - Personnel Correspondence, 1845-1853 (Box 3, Folder 95)
    Photocopies from Superintendent's Letter Book. See Box 3: ff.66.
  - Prices to be Paid Job Hands, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    September 26, 1829.
- Request by Employees for Part of Wages to be Paid to Third Party, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 97)
  September 11, 1829.
  - Memo of the Amount Job Hands Would Have Made at Present Prices, 1829 (Box 3, Folder 98)
  - Sundries Debited to Payroll (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Circa 1830.
  - Averages of Wages, 1839 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    December 1839; May 1839.
  - Prices for Job Hands, 1842 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    October 28, 1842. Piece rates.
  - Overseers' Premium Payments, 1829-1846 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Statement of Time in Employment and Earnings of Each Overseer at Appleton, 1836 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Statement of Time Worked an Earnings of Overseers, 1836 (Box 3, Folder 101)
  - Miscellany, 1850-1855 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    Boardinghouse allowances 1850-1855, number of persons employed by Appleton who did or did not attend meeting ca 1855.
- Series VII. PRODUCTION
  - Inventories, 1829-1841 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    Raw materials and finished cloth, production totals by brand.
  - Rejected Cloth, 1831-1842 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    November 26, 1831; November 1842.
  - Bagging Cloth, 1844 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    May 25, 1844.
  - Statements of cloth manufactured, 1867-1868 (Box 3, Folder 106)
    December 7, 1867 through May 30, 1868.
  - Yards of cloth manufactured (Box 3, Folder 107)
    No date.
  - Spinning Records, 1842-1843 (Box 3, Folder 108)
    May 28, 1842. Memo of Bobbins. June 1843. Yarn twist and number of turns.
  - Weaving Records (Box 2, Folder 21)
    Circa 1830. Memoranda on speeding up of Mill no.2
  - Weaving Records, 1831 (Box 3, Folder 109)
    March 19, 1831. Memoranda on difference in production between looms at high and common speed.
  - Efficiency of Spinning, 1914 (Box 3, Folder 110)
    April 10, 1914. E. Dean Walen.